



Francis Berinyuy Yuyun

Date of birth: 01/04/1999 | **Nationality:** Cameroonian | (+237) 673993113 |

francisberi04@gmail.com | francisberi@afriklewa.com |

https://yuyunfrancis.github.io/francis-portfolio.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuyunfrancis/ | facebook.com/yuyunfrancisberi |

https://twitter.com/FrancisYuyun | Skype: francisyuyun |

Tamtam, Yaounde, Cameroon

About me:

A highly skilled and motivated Software Engineer and a UI/UX Designer with some experience in web design and development knowledge. I am driven to create impacts with the use of technology by providing sustainable solutions to real-world problems. I am dynamic, proactive, hardworking, disciplined, and focused. With these qualities, I am able to withstand any pressure to succeed. I also have strong leadership skills able to motivate and lead people to achieve a common goal and with these leadership skills, I Co-Founded an NGO, Energetic Youths in Action(EYIA) whose primary goal is to help the poor, enhance and encourage youths in all spheres of their lives.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

30/09/2018 - 02/12/2021 - messassi, Yaounde, Cameroon

BACHELOR'S DEGREE OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - The ICT University

https://ictuniversity.org/

21/12/2021 - 21/01/2022 - Online, Cameroon

DIPLOMA MARKETPLACE POSITIONING – The Center For Entrepreneurship, Leadership, and Business Management Development (CELBMD) Africa

https://celbmdafrica.com/

31/10/2020 - 30/11/2020 - Online, Berlin, Germany

BASICS OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT – International Business Management Institute

https://www.ibm-institute.com/

02/09/2017 - 25/06/2021 - Buea, Cameroon

GENERAL CERTIFICATE OF EDUCTION ADVANCED LEVEL – Cameroon General Certificate of Eduction Board

https://camgceb.org/

WORK EXPERIENCE

12/02/2022 - CURRENT - Yaounde, Cameroon

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - KALIO

- Design, develop and test user interface for applications mobile and web
- Intervene throughout the development process of internal applications

- Create reusable code and libraries for future use
- Accurately translate user and business requirements into code functional front end
- Developed new features for users
- Create reusable code and libraries for future use
- Designing UI/UX interfaces
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize the application for maximum speed and scalability
- Make sure that all user input is validated before releasing it, submit to back-end
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- Intervene on the architecture of applications and their implementation
- Intervene in all activities related to previous activities

08/10/2021 - 08/12/2021 - Douala

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN - HANDY SERVICES

- 1. Conceive responsive designs to update the existing website
- 2. Develop the interfaces conceived

06/06/2021 - 06/09/2021 - Douala, Cameroon

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN - ARRAH-SOLUTIONS

- Design, develop and test user interface for applications mobile and web
- Intervene throughout the development process of internal applications
- Create reusable code and libraries for future use
- Accurately translate user and business requirements into code functional front end
- Developed new features for users
- Create reusable code and libraries for future use
- Designing UI/UX interfaces
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize the application for maximum speed and scalability
- Make sure that all user input is validated before releasing it. submit to back-end
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): LAMSO

Other language(s):

	UNDERST	TANDING	SPEA	KING	WRITING	
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C1	
FRENCH	B2	B1	B2	B1	B1	

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Microsoft Excel | microsoft word | microsoft powerpoint | microsoft office | Adobe (Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Indesign, Adobe XD)

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and interpersonal skills

I am very comfortable communicating and understanding different people from different backgrounds and cultures

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

20/04/2022 - 22/04/2022 - Yaounde, Palais de Congres

Cameroon Alumni Nation Symposium organized by he U.S. Exchange Program Alumni Association Cameroon

The U.S-Government -Sponsored Exchange programs are meant to be a support system for the professional capacity to drive expertise influence in creating a positive impact on the economic, social, cultural, and political wellbeing of the concerned beneficiary nations.

www.mwfcameroon.org

02/05/2022 - 06/05/2022 - Douala

Melvira Accademy Training on Leadership and Personal Development, 4E Forum #GiveBack2Community.

Training and developing Future Leaders in Sub Saharan Africa on Soft Skills and EQ, by instilling the Values of Integrity, Compassion, Resilience, Professionalism, and the Power of Positive Thoughts. https://www.linkedin.com/company/melvira-academy/

09/05/2022 - 09/05/2022 - Douala

Youth Entrepreneurship Symposium

Initiated and sponsored by the US Embassy in Yaounde, the Youth Entrepreneurship Symposium is a program aiming at enhancing the capacity of Cameroonian youths in starting and/or developing a business. https://youthentrepreneurshipsymposium.com/

VOLUNTEERING

31/12/2020 - CURRENT

Volunteer and Co-Founder of Energetic Youths in Action

Buea

- 1. To empower and build a team of outstanding self-supporting, self-governing, and self-propagating youths that are committed to helping mankind, especially the vulnerable, needy, women, orphans, youths, and physically challenged.
- 2. Encourage education and vocational training by making sure we send at least an underprivileged to school per year.
- 3. Promote the use of talents among youths.

https://eyiacm.org/volunteers/

HONOURS AND AWARDS

15/04/2022

Premier Dev Tech Innovation Price - Premier Dev

Second Price winner of the tech innovation challenge organized by premier dev. https://www.premierdev.org/

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Co-Founder Energetic Youths in Action

To build a world where we can grow together holding each other's hand as we move ahead thereby bridging the gap between the rich and the poor making life comfortable and bearable for all. https://eyiacm.org/

SPECIALIZATION

Specializations

- Mobile App Development (React Native)
- Frontend Web Developer (React Js)
- Programming Languages (Python)
- Content Writer
- Intermediate Graphic Designer
- UI/UX Designer (Adobe XD, Figma)
- Project Management Skills
- Database Management (MYSQL)
- Leadership

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS					
Listening to Music					
Watching Movies					
Basketball					
Gym					